# Ryan ROSELLO

**EMAIL**: roselloryan@gmail.com

**PHONE:** 813.545.2666

**GITHUB:** www.github.com/roselloryan

TWITTER: @roselloryan

**BLOG:** www.medium.com/@roselloryan LINKEDIN: www.linkedin.com/in/roselloryan



### BIO

Jazz took me around the world teaching me about patterns, people, and art. Pre-med curriculum and medical research taught me about science, math and the human condition. After working as an insurance biller for a physical therapy clinic, I decided to return to school to study medicine. I found coding along the way while studying for the MCAT. It was an enjoyable relief from studying anatomy, med school applications and seemingly brought together all of my past experiences in a way I had never experienced before.

After brief introductions to HTML, Python, and JavaScript on Codecademy, I met with various types of programmers to get a better idea of different career paths. I was most excited by the iOS engineers work and knew this was my next step. I enrolled in the immersive iOS development course at the Flatiron School and have spent every day since working to learn the skills needed to be a valued mobile developer and contributing team member.

### APPLICATIONS BUILT

<u>Celsius and Fahrenheit</u> - Current temp in °C and °F with animated illustrations for weather conditions for cities around the world. Available in the App Store.

- + References OpenWeatherMap API to access current weather conditions for +200k cities
- + Persists data using Core Data framework
- + Utilizes MapKit framework for user to select city if more than one location has the same name
- + Features all original illustrations with charming animations SceneKit parti
- + iOS Today extension using Core Location framework displays current city, temps and weather condition icon
- + GitHub repository

<u>Project Mailbox</u> - Bringing intimacy back to social media. Invitation only groups for sharing pictures, songs, thoughts, or drawings.

- + Utilized Parse cloud based data storage for user content storage and retrieval
- + Implemented iOS Share extension to post songs to our app from within Spotify app
- + Integrated Spotify iOS SDK to allow in app streaming of shared Spotify songs
- + Used third party framework to allow users to create and post drawings

**Space POD App** - displays NASA picture of the day plus sounds from space to amaze and inspire.

- + Fetches Astronomy picture of the days from NASA api
- + Retrieves, stores, and plays tracks from NASA SoundCloud playlists
- + Incorporates various animations for floating playback buttons



# EDUCATION

## **Columbia University**, 2014

Certificate in Premedical Sciences, Healthcare/Research

## **University Of North Florida**, 2006

Bachelor of Arts (B.A.), Music/Jazz studies

#### **FMPI OYMENT HISTORY**

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY			
<b>T2 Multisport NYC</b> New York, NY	<b>Miccass Physical</b> <b>Therapy</b> New York, NY	NYU School Of Medicine at Bellevue Hospital New York, NY	<b>Sports Physical Therapy Of New York</b> New York, NY
Systems Manager/USA Cycling Coach	Physical Therapy Aide	Emergency Research Volunteer (PAVERS)	PCS/Biller
Feb. 2015 - Sept. 2015	Dec. 2014 - Sept. 2015	August 2013 - May 2015	August 2010 - April 2012
+ Set up computers and calibrate sensors for 18 training stations that measure power output	+ Led patients, one on one, through physical therapy programs to help heal and regain function	+ Screened and enrolled patients in active studies to decrease patient exposure to radiation	+ Maintained patient treatment information authorizations, prescriptions, and plans of care
+ Tested athlete power output and endurance to quantify performance change  + Improved cyclists' FTP	+ Demonstrated proper technique for stretches and exercises preventing injury	+ Processed data from abdominal and cardiac ultrasound scans including vitals, blood levels, findings and final diagnosis	+ Audited treatment notes for accurate treatment times and CPT codes
(functional threshold power) and power to weight ratio (W/Lb)	+ Adjusted program intensity for patients to safely gain strength and flexibility	+ Assisted physicians with emergency procedures in trauma	+ Scheduled patient appointments and applied account payments
+ Designed power zone training sessions that increased rider FTP by 30% over 6 months time	+ Verified insurance authorization details for accurate billing	<ul><li>bay</li><li>+ Performed patient electrocardiogram tests</li></ul>	+ Initiated successful employee fitness challenge

(ECG, EKG)